Isabela Monteiro

github.com/Isabelaluizi isabelamonteiro.ml

(587) 434 2087

Email:isabelaluizi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/isabelaluizimonteiro

SUMMARY

A self-motivated, proactive and adaptable professional holding a Diploma in Web Development and BSC in Chemical Engineering. Problem solving and teamwork skills developed in 5+ years of experience in the Oil and Gas industry; advanced English and Spanish languages proficiency and full fluency in Portuguese.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML

PHP

JavaScript

SQL

Vue.js

WordPress

Git/Github

CSS

Laravel

SCSS

Bootstrap

Materialize

• MS Office -Excel, Word, PowerPoint

EDUCATION

Diploma Web Development InnoTech College, Calgary AB Oct 2019 - May 2020

Specialized in Energy Engineering UERJ, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

2018 - 2019

Bachelor in Chemical Engineering

2008 - 2014

PUC-RIO, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Degree evaluated as equivalent to Canadian degree by World Education Services - WES

International Exchange Program

2012 - 2013

Universidad de Cadiz, Cadiz, Spain

PROJECTS

TWEETER 2020

A social media website built with Laravel, Vuejs and MySQL.

Full stack coding project.

Website: https://tweeterproject.ml/

Github: https://github.com/Isabelaluizi/TweeterTwo

COFFEE LOVERS 2020

A coffee reviewer website built with Laravel, Vuejs and MySQL.

• Full stack coding project.

Website: https://coffeelovers.tk/

Github: https://github.com/lsabelaluizi/coffeelovers

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE Apr 2019 – Present

Formula Canada Immigration, Calgary, AB

- Translated documents from English and Spanish to Portuguese
- Promoted and solicited orders for the sale of the Company's products and services
- Provided administrative support related to clients referred for immigration services

COMMERCIAL ANALYST

Aug 2014 - Dec 2018

REPSOL SINOPEC, Rio de Janerio, Brazil

- Developed projects aimed at future gas sales strategies in collaboration with asset and economic teams
- Identified error in invoice by comparing numbers in the sales agreement contracts which resulted in savings of ~\$2M US for the company
- Presented Natural Gas analysis to Repsol Board of Directors (local and international)
- Completed supply, demand, infrastructure, and price Natural Gas Market Studies by gathering and analyzing data from more than 10 different public and private sources
- Created an automated Natural Gas flow model which included more than 9 thousand kilometres of pipeline; model was used to analyze possible bottlenecks in the infrastructure, and was presented and recognized by the Brazilian government
- Negotiated gas sales with existing and potential clients which resulted in a signed sales agreement
- Analyzed gas prices and developed a comprehensive study of potential profits and expenses for potential customers
- Prepared quarterly Natural Gas, LNG and NGL price forecasts and reported to the economic team
- Analyzed and tracked regulatory changes in the Brazilian gas market which resulted in a better understanding of the gas market trends to support the future gas sales strategies
- Managed the income and expense budget for the department which reported financial data

GAS COMMERCIALIZATION INTERN

Sep 2013 – Jul 2014

REPSOL SINOPEC, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

• Trained as a commercial analyst

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Student Mentor

May 2019 – Jul 2019

Bow Valley College, Calgary, AB

Assisted college students with in-class typing assignments